healthdiscovery.net 2017-06-06

# Our Privacy Policy, Legal Disclaimer, and Terms of Use | Health Discovery

Health Discovery takes the issue of safeguarding your privacy on-line very seriously. We have strict policies and procedures designed to protect the privacy of our visitors. We will never share your personal information with any external organization without your consent. We do not sell any personal information about our visitors, including email addresses, ever. Any personal information you do wish to provide is protected internally, but should not be considered secure from unauthorized access.  

## Details about information collected and used on this site:

### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data temporarily stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site (who you are, your email address, or anything personal). The cookie helps the user to save time. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. Web browsers can be set to reject cookies. If a user rejects the cookie they may still use our site, but may not be able to take advantage of certain features - such as logging into your user account. Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. Cookies help us evaluate your use of our site, such as what kind of information you want to see and what kind you will never read. Cookie technology allows Web sites to ask for your registration and preference questions only once. The next time you return to the Web site you will not necessarily need to "sign in" again. Remember that cookies are "non-executable" pieces of code; that is, they are incapable of doing anything to your hard drive. It is possible that your 'cookies' could be read by other websites - typically used to display relevant content across the internet. Cookies are easy to delete from your hard drive; talk to your systems administrator or your Internet provider for detailed instructions.

### Log Files

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user preferences, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information on our site, and not visible to any other users.

### Forums, Blogs, Comments, and other Public Discussions

Our Online Discussion Groups have a bulletin board format that allows our visitors the opportunity to interact with our online community. These areas are moderated by volunteer hosts, strictly to keep inappropriate messages from being posted. You are offered the opportunity to include your email address with your message, and your birthday in your profile - but you are not obligated to do so. If you do include these and have activated the option to show them - then it is visible to the general public on the bulletin board. We cannot control the actions of any third parties use of public information. We do not sell any email addresses from our bulletin boards. Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on public message boards, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online. Think before you post, and be sure of your of your privacy settings!

### Newsletter

If you decide to submit your email address to us in order to be added to our mailing list, you may be assured that you will not receive separate emails from other marketers as a result of joining our newsletter. You will receive no offers from our sites other than those made through the newsletter itself, which, of course, you have elected to receive. You may unsubscribe at any time through our unsubscribe page. Surveys & Contests From time to time Health Discovery requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Some of the information requested is of a personal nature but there is certainly no obligation to answer every question. In particular, submission of your email address is entirely optional. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Large population demographics may be compiled and published using this data but no individual information is ever disseminated.

### Third-Party Sharing

From time to time we may partner with another party to provide specific services. When a user signs up for these services, we will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. We do use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information ( **not including** your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

Our partners and other third-party sites and services accessible through our site, have separate privacy and data collection practices, independent of us. Healthdiscovery.net and it's owner has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies or actions.

### Links to Other Sites

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Health Discovery is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collect personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected on this website site only. We do have a strict anti-spam policy. No user is allowed to post an outgoing link without consent. Links are subjected to approval and security scanning.

### Advertising Policy

We do have some advertisements in place to financially support our free-of-charge community and the overhead of running the servers and software required. HealthDiscovery.net does not endorse any of the advertised products/services that we display, nor do we have total control of what some of our advertisers choose to display in their allowed locations. We make every effort to avoid advertisements that do not comply with the site editorial policy, and have chosen only advertisers with reputations for safety and security of site visitors.

### Choice/Opt-out

Our users are given the opportunity to "opt-out" of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information. For example, our message board will have an "opt-out" mechanism so users can keep their e-mail address off our lists. Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials from our partners may opt-out of receiving this communications using our un-subscribe option. Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether they should proceed with services that require an outside party, or not.

### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our Homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. Protecting the privacy of our visitors is our topmost concern.

## HealthDiscovery.net Legal Disclaimer

Though we do strive to provide factual and correct information, we do not imply or guarantee that everything you discover on our site is accurate, or of good sounded advice. All material on HealthDiscovery.net is intended for your general knowledge only, and is not a substitute for professional medical advice, or treatment for any specific medical conditions. You should seek prompt medical care for any specific health issues, and consult your physician before starting a new diet or fitness regimen. 

### Restaurants:

The information we use generally comes directly from the establishments current nutrition and allergen guides. We make no assertions that this information has been input correct on our website, or that variations have not caused inaccuracies in our current information. We waive any responsibility of any outcome from the use of our listings. Again, these are a general reference only. If you have allergies, or other medical complications from food - Talk to your doctor, and the restaurant manger before your eat out. Don't go by what some website or piece of paper tells you.

Additionally, we claim no ownership to the use of any trademarks on this website. We are not selling any products in their name, or providing any services under such names. The information provided for these items is public information which has been put forth as news. All Trademark names and associated products are the property of their respective owners. We only provide information here.

### Weight Watchers:

We are not affiliated with Weight Watchers International - official information about Weight Watchers, and authentic Points values can only be found by joining Weight Watchers Online, or attending local meetings. We encourage you to do so! They are the superior weight-loss program, and it works! Which is why we have decided to include simulations of Points, that are not exactly the same as their official Points programs. Though we do admire the science and research behind them, we have provided our own rendition of mathematics that happens to be a very, very, close estimate. We claim no rights to the usage of Points, PointsPlus, or SmartPoints, and again provide this information only as news.

### Other Information

This website is not owned by any organization or for-profit venture. It is owned and operated by a sole individual as a blog-like website, to provide free assistance and information for other individuals online seeking to choose healthy lifestyles. The owner of this site claims no legal responsibility and will not be held liable for any use of such information, use of this website, or for any postings provided by other parties.

By using our website you agree to the practices and disclaimers we have placed, as well as anything we may have accidentally omitted, mistyped, or introduce in the future.
